# Jonathan Hindi

# User Experience Designer

11 years of working experience with small businesses and startup companies; 5 years of which have been in User Experience helping grow startups such as Flywheel, BuildFire, Cabulous and KaleoApps with an emphasis on mobile and web development.

#### **Work Experience**

## BuildFire - UX Designer (May 2014 - Present)

<u>BuildFire</u> is a startup company that provides a CMS for phone applications which work on both Android and iOS using PhoneGap technology. This is a particularly interesting position. With three different types of users, I have to integrate all platforms and services to all levels of clients and maintain the flow of information with the proper permissions. My responsibilities are:

- Communicating with product and development teams
- Drawing out logic flow charts
- Draw out the transfer of information from one platform to the other
- Help develop the products and features
- Design UX wireframes
- QA and support

<u>Featured in Businesses News Daily</u> as the number one app builder for ease of use Featured in <u>Yahoo News</u> as the easiest app builder

# KaleoApps - UX Designer (July 2013 - May 2014)

<u>KaleoApps</u> is a startup company which targets non-profit organizations. They provide a digital donation platform and developed mobile applications. Working with a third party vendor and branching out to allow white labeling was a very interesting task to take on. In this position I learned how to accommodate multiple demands coming from multiple businesses and keep up with a UX that is flexible and agnostic enough to allow any user with any information to create a full and beautiful product. My responsibilities included:

- Maintaining business relationships and goals
- Designed logic work flow and UX wireframes
- Product development
- Designing responsive web and mobile interfaces
- Front end development

#### Flywheel – UX Designer (Feb 2012 – Dec 2013)

<u>Flywheel</u> is a company that provides a geo-tracking software solutions that can be implemented on any smartphone. This challenging opportunity pushed me to fully embrace native UX. We were creating three main platforms web, native Android and iOS. Keeping in mind that the product was still being developed and refined, my responsibilities were:

- Converting simple logic workflows to full UX wireframes for web, Android & iOS
- Product development

- Designing assets for both Android & iOS plus extraction & optimization
- Front end development
- Android XML layout development

## Cabulous – UX Designer (Oct 2010 – Feb 2012)

Cabulous is a startup company which provides an automated system that mediates between cab drivers/fleets and their passengers. It also provided a dispatch system and tracker for dispatchers and fleet owners. In this unique dynamics of integration, I was able to bring forth a dispatch system that was easier, faster and more comprehensive than what the cab industry currently used. I was also able to bring forth a user friendly app that allowed users to select rides directly and easily with a two-step process. My responsibilities included:

- Product development
- Designing logic workflows
- Designing native UX wireframes
- Designing responsive platforms that embraced native tools
- Front end development
- QA and Support

# LA Law Library - Communication Coordinator (Dec 2010 - Feb 2012)

<u>LALL</u> is the second largest legal library in the US. I came in when the Library was ready to completely reinvent itself from being a warehouse of books to a leader in research technology. I was responsible for:

- Creating communication strategies and marketing efforts
- Designing communication materials, both digital and print
- Organizing events such as Galas
- Web site maintenance and updates
- Developing mass email blasts
- Organizing and designing booths and communication material in events and conferences

## Magnify 360 – Front End Web Developer (Sep 2010 – Dec 2010)

<u>A SEO optimization company</u> serving clients such as Intuit®, MasterCard®, netSpend™, Seagate® among others. Through their patented software they customized landing pages for SEO purposes and helped generate higher click through rates. My role included:

- Front end development
- Extraction and optimization assets
- Designing landing pages, e-banners and ads

#### Safe Mode Services - Owner (Aug 2009 - Dec 2013)

A business created to satisfy any technical and marketing need. Clients served:

- Vitro An advertisement agency serving clients such as: Budweiser, Land Rover, Asics
- MadainCorp A software service provider
- **GGothika** Gothic jewelry owned by a gold smith dealing with precise stones
- **WeNominate.com** A voting site similar to Yelp
- Top To Toe Mobile In home SPA service
- **Skin Body Lounge** SPA and lounge
- All Star Video Games Ecommerce site, specializing in vintage video games
- City Wide Dispatch A cab dispatcher
- Cam Caddie Wholesaler, providing camera accessories
- **Hefner Property Management** Business property management company
- Among other companies

### **Skills & Qualifications**

## **Skills & Technologies**

- CS 6 (Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesgin, Flash ...ect)
- HTML5
- CSS 2,3
- JS, JQuery & other libraries
- SEM, SEO
- PhoneGap
- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint ... ect)
- Visio

#### **Personal Skills**

- Self-managed & Self-motivated
- Attention to detail while maintaining the road map in mind
- Very well organized
- Multi-tasking

# Leadership & Added Value

- Cross-functional supervision
- Team building, mentoring & stress management
- Client relations & presentation
- Business & IT planning
- Product development

## Education

## California State University, Northridge

BS, Marketing

2010